<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: os | ashinkarov.github.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://ashinkarov.github.com/blog/categories/os/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ashinkarov.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-07-16T07:19:13+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://ashinkarov.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Artem Shinkarov]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Teaching operating systems]]></title>
    <link href="http://ashinkarov.github.com/blog/2013/02/01/teaching-operating-systems/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-01T20:16:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ashinkarov.github.com/blog/2013/02/01/teaching-operating-systems</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Teaching process should be fun and enjoyable for both parties: students and
teachers, otherwise it doesn't make much of a sense.  Studying operating systems
might become relatively complex endeavour as it normally includes a lot of
technical details, alternatives in designs and some low level programming. Also,
the amount of code that one might have to deal with could be really frightening.</p>

<p>In order to compensate the overall struggle, I've decided to concentrate on
the way things are named in UNIX-flavoured OS-es.  The naming convention of
different types of processes is pretty much amusing if you think about it.
I don't know who started it, but it has very noticeable demoniacal connotations:
<em>daemons</em>, <em>zombies</em>, <em>killing parents</em>, <em>orphans</em>, etc.  Sounds quite scary,
isn't it?  Following that train of thought, I managed to come up with the
following assignment:</p>

<pre><code>Answer the following questions providing reasonable explanations:

1. What happens when a child kills its parent?
2. Can a zombie do so, or it is too dead for that?
3. Can a daemon become a zombie?
4. How long can an orphan live on it's own, if at all?
</code></pre>

<p>I hope that it would add some giggle to the overall struggle.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
