<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: thoughts | ashinkarov.github.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://ashinkarov.github.com/blog/categories/thoughts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ashinkarov.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-10-15T15:12:13+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://ashinkarov.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Artem Shinkarov]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon luck had left me]]></title>
    <link href="http://ashinkarov.github.com/blog/2013/01/31/amazon-luck-left-me/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-31T18:30:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ashinkarov.github.com/blog/2013/01/31/amazon-luck-left-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I moved to the UK, three years ago, I was really amazed to see how
simple it is to buy things online.  Keep in mind that in the place where
I lived before, people did not have a lot of trust in the post, so in the
beginning the British system truly amazed me.  Three years later I am
reconsidering this statement.</p>

<!-- more-->


<p>On the unrelated note, I had a discussion once with my German colleague
and he was vastly complaining about the British post.  When I asked to
explain the matter, he said that since he moved into the UK, eight years
ago, the post managed to lose three parcels.  In Germany that would never
happened, he concluded.</p>

<p>Well, it indicates that different people have different expectations form
the system, and if you would ever dare to complain to a Russian guy about
the three parcels, he would laugh into your face.</p>

<p>Coming back to the subject, very quickly I was hooked on Amazon, as it
kind of works.</p>

<h1>Amazon</h1>

<p>Amazon has a great experience in online selling so they managed to come
to the point that new customers wish to stay with them.  Actually it is
a great job, and I wonder how many psychologists, web designers, etc. it
took to come to the current state.</p>

<p>Obviously, the killing feature is the globalisation.  They create a
meta-online shop which redirects requests to the actual sellers.  The
laziness is the driving force of progress so people adopted and appreciated
the system very quickly .  Being in their current position they can give
very competitive prices, thanks to <em>google shopping</em> service it is easy to
check.  They unify the way you communicate, pay, receive, etc. and make it
easy.  As apple slogan says -- "it just works".</p>

<p>Now, most of the layered system do not work equally well in both
directions, and Amazon is not exception here.  Amazon woks perfectly well
until you don't have to return items.  It has a simple explanation --
people prefer to receive money rather than pay money.  Fair enough.</p>

<p>Again, as a matter of fact, most of the time a person is happy with the
stuff he is receiving.  So as a seller you might want to consider that.
You might want to include this into your budget planning.  Especially
cheeky sellers can make returns arbitrary hard in order to discourage
people from doing so.</p>

<h1>Amazon returns</h1>

<p>If you order stuff from Amazon itself, the returns are done very decently.
It does not ask any stupid questions and immediately gives
you a pre-paid sticker which you put on your item and post it back.  Well
done Amazon, highly appreciated.  When it comes to the marketplace -- then
the hell breaks loose.</p>

<p>It is crucially important to realise that in essence there are two
different processes involved -- if you buy from Amazon itself, or if you
go to the <em>marketplace</em>.  The marketplace is a term they use to indicate that
they just act as a front-end for sellers and all the real stuff is going
to be done by sellers, not by the Amazon itself.</p>

<p>Here comes the confusion.  Amazon tries to have the same look and feel
no matter what you do, so in a way, the fact that you are potentially
engaging with a third party, by making purchases at marketplace, is
carefully hidden from you.  Dear Amazon, why don't you unify return
procedures for all your customers on the marketplace, ah?  That would
really fix the user experience, and we will be able to conclude that
the layered approach works equally well both ways?  Are you going to lose
part of your sellers?  Or would it create more work for you?   I doubt it.</p>

<h1>Case Study</h1>

<p>In the middle of December I bought a backpack from Amaon marketplace,
as I needed a replacement for my old one.  After some googling I have
chosen <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B001IBHSUK/ref=oh_details_o06_s00_i00">this one</a>
with a nice red cross.  Then I left the country for Christmas holidays and
came back on 12-th of January.  The backpack was waiting for me, and the
red cross was shining exactly as it did at the picture.  I decided to give
it a try, and it wasn't bad at all.  Later I discovered that the thing is
leaking in the rain.  Well, the laptop bag which is leaking in the rain is
less than usable for me.  Keep in mind, that I live in Scotland, and I
think I don't need to say too much about the rain here.</p>

<p>Now I've checked if I still can return it, and the web page happily said
that:</p>

<pre><code>    ... the return window will close on 31 Jan 2013. Please note that this is
    currently extended for the holidays and not all sellers offer an extended
    return window ...
</code></pre>

<p>Well done Amazon, I thought, so I pressed the "Return" button and carefully
explained the situation to the seller.  Few hours later I received the
following response:</p>

<pre><code>    Thank you for your email.

    Unfortunately. we are unable to accept the return of this item as
    it is not described to be water proof.
    If you require further assistance, please let us know.

    To respond to this email, please kindly reply leaving the subject
    title intact.

    Yours sincerely,

    Jas
    Kikatek Customer Support Team
</code></pre>

<p>You must be bloody joking, Jas, I thought.  I really don't know who are
you, Jas, I am not even sure about your sex, but isn't it just ridiculous?
The manual of a new car does not specify that it is not leaking, however
application of common sense might help.  Also, the fact that implication
from false leads to both true and false is amusing, but do you really want
to use it as an argument?</p>

<p>Explaining my thoughts and trying to be polite, I replied to the email,
but then they just didn't respond to it.  This habit, very common in the
UK, just pisses me off!  This bloody face-saving crap, it is everywhere.
There are plenty ways of terminating conversation politely, but not
responding is <em>not</em> one of them!</p>

<p>Fine, they just want to wait until the "return window" would be closed
and use it as an argument later, I thought.  So I wrote to the Amazon
asking for advice, and they suggested to write a claim.  I did so, which
caused immediate response from the seller, saying that the return is
authorised.</p>

<p>Right, now the annoying part of the story is that you have to pay yourself
the postage of the item which, by the way costs about 10 pounds.  And I am
not really sure if they ever going to refund that.</p>

<p>Now, after later investigation, I have learned that this "extension" has
a tiny comment which you cannot really see when you look at your order:</p>

<pre><code>     Please note that this doesn't apply to items sold and fulfilled by
     Sellers on Amazon Marketplace. For information about returns to
     Sellers please see our Arranging Marketplace Returns and Refunds
     help page
</code></pre>

<p>Further more, the Kikatek  has some policies on the returned items
regarding the way they are going to refund it.</p>

<p>To be continued...</p>

<h1>Conclusions</h1>

<p>A simple thing is turning into a nightmare.  You just waste time on stupid
emails and claims and what have you.  Of course, you can say -- hell with
that, I'll buy a rain cover or solve it differently.</p>

<p>My point is that by not unifying return policies for all the users, Amazon
is spoiling the user experience.  I do understand that in general a return
should be complicated to discourage buyers from returning everything, but
why don't you make it equally complicated?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
